A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Audiovisual materials, Series R FA755
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Audiovisual materials, Series R
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich) (1908-1979)
FA755
14 Reels
Conditions Governing Access
This series is open for research. When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Scope and Contents
Personal films
Moving Images
- Nelson A. Rockefeller, Personal films, 1930-1973; R
  Arrangement
  Alphabetical.
  Scope and Contents
  A group of amateur and professional films, television episodes, etc., belonging to or featuring NAR.
  - The Art of Collecting, 1964; Sound, Color, 40 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1072)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Open for research. Digital access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
    Scope and Contents note
    NBC documentary on wealthy figures and their various collections, including interview with Nelson Rockefeller in the Executive Mansion in Albany. Nelson Rockefeller appears in final portion of the program.
  - Cancer Cures, Sound, Color, 25 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1838)
    Segment from CBS-TV "60 Minutes."
  - First Baby Atom Blast, 1955 February 18; Black and white, 1 minute; 16mm film (Reel AV 1188)
    Footage of a nuclear test explosion.
  - Maragoli: A Population Study, Sound, Color, 50 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1932)
    Documentary on overpopulation in Western Kenya.
  - NASA Astronaut Film, 1969 January 10 (Event Date); Sound, Color, 5 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1254)
    Film of Apollo VIII mission, narrated by Art Fleming, which was shown at a New York State dinner for the Apollo VIII astronauts and their wives (1969 January 10).
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller: Dartmouth Reunion I, 1935; Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1410)
    1935 footage from Class of 1930 reunion in Hanover VT: classmates join baseball game on campus, marching band, picnic on the Haffenraffer Estate, etc.
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller: Dartmouth Reunion II, Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1409)
    Hanover, VT: Senior class officers, Alpha Delta Phi fraternity baseball game, Beth Theta Pi group in front of house, Psi Upsilon baseball game, Sigma Alpha Epsilon play cards; views of Dartmouth campus; hazing scene with men dressed liked babies in competition for "cutest baby".
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Dartmouth Reunion III, Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1408)
    Hanover, VT: group shots of classmates with wives, classic car scenes, swimming and baseball.
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family Film II, 1940s; Silent, color, 9 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1068)
    1940s footage of Nelson Rockefeller family on vacations: Yellowstone Park WY at Old Faithful, at Jackson Lake Lodge, riding horses; playing at Seal Harbor, twins on the beach; Pocantico Hills-Hawes House, visiting with JDR JR and Abby, sailing boats.
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family III, 1950; Silent, Color, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1069)
    1950 footage of the family playing at Pocantico Hills with John D. Rockefeller Jr.: playing in pool, eating on patio; additional footage from the graduation of Steven Rockefeller from Princeton University.
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family IV, 1930s-1940s; Silent, Color and Black and white, 11 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1070)
    1930s and 1940s travel footage from Asia and the western United States. Nelson A. Rockefeller and Mary Toddhunter Clark Rockefeller in the Far East. Footage includes scenes of Chinese boat and rice paddies. Footage of Pocantico Hills with scenes of Mary Toddhunter Clark Rockefeller playing with the children in the garden, miscellenous footage of the western United States, and scenes of Mary Toddhunter Clark Rockefeller and children playing in Seal Harbor at the beach.
  - Ronald Reagan Speech at Disneyland Hotel, 1973 September 12; 16mm film (Reel AV 1927A)
    Ronald Reagan address to the California Bar Association, at the Disneyland Hotel.
  - Rodman Rockefeller on Newsfront, 1968 May 18; Sound, Black and white, 13 minutes; 16mm film (Reel AV 1100)
    Open for research. Digital access copy available.
    New York City NY: interview about history of the International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC).